<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="toxic_plants">
        <item>Castor bean</item>
        <item>Autumn crocus</item>
        <item>Datura</item>
        <item>Oleander</item>
        <item>Dieffenbachia</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="toxic_plants_details">
        <item>Castor bean plant:\n
Ornamental plant\n
The highest concentration of toxin is in the seed coating, especially when chewed.\n
Symptoms start 2 to 24 hours after ingestion and can last for several days.\n
Symptoms of poisoning:\n
Severe gastrointestinal symptoms such as repeated nausea and vomiting, abdominal pain – dehydration.\n
If symptoms appear or poisoning is suspected, give the child water and fluids, keep them cool and calm, and take them to the poison emergency center.</item>
        <item>When flowering, it resembles saffron; when not, it looks like wild garlic.\n
It remains toxic even when cooked.\n
Symptoms of autumn crocus poisoning:\n
Day 1: nausea – vomiting – severe or bloody watery diarrhea\n
Days 2 to 7: low blood pressure and heart rate – excessive sweating\n
Day 7: symptoms become very serious and life-threatening.\n
If symptoms appear or poisoning is suspected, give the child water and fluids, keep them cool and calm, and take them to the poison emergency center.</item>
        <item>All parts of the plant are toxic.\n
The seed is the most toxic part.\n
Onset of symptoms:\n
1-4 hours after ingestion, symptoms appear and can last up to 48 hours or more.\n
Symptoms of Datura poisoning:\n
Restlessness – increased heart rate – hallucinations – dry skin and mouth – euphoria.\n
If symptoms appear or poisoning is suspected, give the child water and fluids, keep them cool and calm, and take them to the poison emergency center.</item>
        <item>All parts of the plant are toxic.\n
Symptoms of oleander poisoning:\n
Nausea, vomiting, abdominal pain, loss of appetite, lethargy, heart complications, and possibly confusion.\n
If symptoms appear or poisoning is suspected, give the child water and fluids, keep them cool and calm, and take them to the poison emergency center.</item>
        <item>This is a decorative houseplant that, when its leaves are torn, exudes a milky sap that can cause irritation and inflammation on contact with skin, mucous membranes, or eyes.\n
Symptoms of Dieffenbachia poisoning:\n
Contact with skin or ingestion of the sap causes pain, redness, and swelling of the lips, which can become severe.\n
Action required:\n
Wash the child’s skin and mouth thoroughly with cool water, give them milk or cool water to drink, apply a cold compress to the skin, and if symptoms of poisoning appear, take them to the poison emergency center.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="toxic_drugs">
        <item>Cannabis (Hashish)</item>
        <item>Opium and derivatives</item>
        <item>Methamphetamine</item>
        <item>Alcohol (ethanol, methanol)</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="toxic_drug_symptom">
        <item>Euphoria – auditory perception disturbance – restlessness in children especially infants – drowsiness – eye redness – dry mouth</item>
        <item>Nausea, vomiting\n
Itching: common around eyes and nose\n
Decreased consciousness (from drowsiness to deep coma)</item>
        <item>Most common symptom in children:\n
Increased heart rate\n
Repetitive aimless movements\n
Increased sweating\n
Muscle stiffness</item>
        <item>Symptoms of ethanol poisoning:\n
Nausea and vomiting,\n
Drunken state\n
Low blood sugar\n
Symptoms of methanol poisoning:\n
Dangerous symptoms occur 12 to 24 hours later\n
Initial symptoms:\n
Nausea and vomiting\n
Delayed vision symptoms: narrowing visual field, blurred vision\n
Color vision disturbance (black and white vision)</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="toxic_drug_caution">
        <item>If symptoms appear or poisoning is suspected, keep the child cool and calm, and take them to the poison emergency center.</item>
        <item>If symptoms appear what should we do?\n
The most important thing is to keep the child awake and make sure they are breathing well.\n
Keep them awake even by physical stimulation.\n
Give the child water and fluids.</item>
        <item>If symptoms appear or poisoning is suspected, keep the child cool and calm, and take them to the poison emergency center.</item>
        <item>Ethanol:\n
If symptoms appear or poisoning is suspected, keep the child cool and calm, give them water and fluids, and take them to the poison emergency center.\n
Methanol:\n
If symptoms appear or poisoning is suspected, take the child immediately to the poison emergency center.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="toxic_drug_family">
        <item></item>
        <item>In addition to opium itself, the following medicines are also opium derivatives:\n
Methadone tablets or syrup\n
Buprenorphine sublingual tablets (B2)\n
Oxycodone tablets\n
Tramadol tablets\n
Loperamide tablets or syrup\n
Dextromethorphan tablets or syrup\n
Opium syrup</item>
        <item>In addition to meth itself, the following may contain meth components:\n
Pseudoephedrine tablets or syrup\n
Some unauthorized weight loss products</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="toxic_drugs_ways">
        <item>Oral\n
Inhaled\n
Sometimes in cakes and pastries</item>
        <item>Oral\n
Inhaled\n
Nasal\n
Through skin\n
Rectal</item>
        <item>Inhaled\n
Oral, even in small amounts</item>
        <item>Oral</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="toxic_med_names">
        <item>Iron</item>
        <item>Vitamin D</item>
        <item>Acetaminophen</item>
        <item>Ibuprofen</item>
        <item>Antihistamines</item>
        <item>Ritalin</item>
        <item>Phenobarbital</item>
        <item>Risperidone</item>
        <item>Metoclopramide</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="toxic_med_detail">
        <item></item>
        <item>The dose that causes poisoning varies between individuals; generally in children under 6 months maximum 1000 units daily, over 6 months maximum 4500 units daily.\n
Symptoms of Vitamin D poisoning:\n
Loss of appetite, nausea, vomiting, constipation, abdominal pain, dry mouth, increased urination</item>
        <item>Initial symptoms of acetaminophen poisoning:\n
Nausea, vomiting, loss of appetite, weakness\n
Toxic dose: over 150 mg per kg of body weight.\n
Even if the child seems fine, if they consumed more than the allowed dose or show symptoms, take them to the poison emergency center.</item>
        <item>Symptoms of ibuprofen poisoning:\n
Usually within 4-6 hours of intake.\n
Gastrointestinal: nausea, vomiting, abdominal pain, headache\n
Possible asthma attack.\n
Avoid giving to young children on an empty stomach for fever.\n
If poisoning is suspected or symptoms appear, take to the poison emergency center.</item>
        <item>Antihistamines include:\n
Chlorpheniramine, Cyproheptadine, Diphenhydramine, Hydroxyzine, Promethazine, Cetirizine, Desloratadine, Loratadine, Fexofenadine, Famotidine\n
Symptoms:\n
Dry and red skin, restlessness, decreased urination\n
What to do:\n
Keep child cool and calm, give water and fluids, take to the poison emergency center.</item>
        <item>Symptoms of Ritalin poisoning:\n
Increased heart rate, possibly high blood pressure\n
Euphoria, dehydration, headache, delirium\n
Repetitive movements like lip sucking, muscle stiffness, immobility\n
If symptoms appear, take to the poison emergency center.</item>
        <item>Symptoms of phenobarbital poisoning:\n
Drowsiness, decreased heart rate, cold hands and feet, possible skin blisters\n
If symptoms appear, take to the poison emergency center.</item>
        <item>Symptoms:\n
Can occur hours to days after intake, not dose dependent.\n
Involuntary, uncoordinated movements (e.g. facial distortion, eye deviation, speech disturbance, inability to swallow)\n
If symptoms appear, take to the poison emergency center.</item>
        <item>Preferably avoid use under age 2.\n
Symptoms:\n
Can occur hours to days after intake, not dose dependent.\n
Involuntary, uncoordinated movements (e.g. facial distortion, eye deviation, speech disturbance, inability to swallow)\n
If symptoms appear, take to the poison emergency center.</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>