<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="vaccine_names">
        <item>Meningococcal Conjugate</item>
        <item>Influenza Vaccine</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="vaccine_wrong">
        <item>Recent exposure to an infectious disease</item>
        <item>Mild illness with low-grade fever such as cold, ear infection, or mild diarrhea</item>
        <item>Convalescence period of a disease</item>
        <item>Receiving antibiotics except for oral typhoid vaccine</item>
        <item>Receiving antiviral drugs except for chickenpox and live influenza vaccine</item>
        <item>Premature infant or low birth weight except BCG in infants under 33 weeks</item>
        <item>Household contact with a pregnant woman</item>
        <item>History of mild or nonspecific allergy in the vaccine recipient or relatives</item>
        <item>Breastfeeding</item>
        <item>Malnutrition</item>
        <item>Neonatal jaundice</item>
        <item>Family history of sudden infant death syndrome</item>
        <item>Household contact with an immunodeficient person except in special cases (e.g., oral polio vaccine — inform the health center)</item>
        <item>Recent surgery or surgery planned in the near future</item>
        <item>Chronic non-communicable diseases of the heart and lungs (such as asthma), kidney, liver, or metabolic diseases like diabetes</item>
        <item>Stable, non-progressive neurological conditions like Down syndrome or cerebral palsy</item>
        <item>Family history of seizures</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="vaccine_use_time">
        <item>At birth</item>
        <item>2 months</item>
        <item>4 months</item>
        <item>6 months</item>
        <item>12 months</item>
        <item>18 months</item>
        <item>5 to 6 years</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="vaccine_time_names">
        <item>BCG vaccine, oral polio vaccine, first dose of hepatitis B vaccine</item>
        <item>Hexavalent vaccine (diphtheria, tetanus, pertussis, hepatitis B, Haemophilus influenzae, polio vaccine)</item>
        <item>Hexavalent vaccine (diphtheria, tetanus, pertussis, hepatitis B, Haemophilus influenzae, polio vaccine)</item>
        <item>Hexavalent vaccine (diphtheria, tetanus, pertussis, hepatitis B, Haemophilus influenzae, polio vaccine, oral polio vaccine, rotavirus vaccine)</item>
        <item>Measles, rubella, mumps vaccine, pneumococcal vaccine</item>
        <item>DTP (diphtheria, tetanus, pertussis) booster, oral polio vaccine, measles, rubella, mumps injectable vaccine</item>
        <item>DTP booster, oral polio vaccine</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="vaccine_use_caution">
        <item>BCG vaccine</item>
        <item>DTP vaccine</item>
        <item>Pediatric DT vaccine</item>
        <item>Oral (OPV) and injectable polio vaccine (IPV) for polio</item>
        <item>MMR vaccine for measles, rubella, mumps</item>
        <item>Tetanus toxoid (TT)</item>
        <item>Hepatitis B</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="vaccine_info">
        <item>According to CDC guidelines, all children aged 11 to 12 years should receive one dose of meningococcal conjugate vaccine. Since immunity from this vaccine decreases over time, those vaccinated before age 16 need a booster dose at least 8 weeks apart, preferably between ages 16 and 18. (CDC recommendation, 2024)</item>

        <item>Children under 13 years:
The first dose of chickenpox vaccine is usually given at 12–15 months and the second at 4–6 years.
The minimum age for the first dose is 12 months.
If a dose is given before 12 months, it is not valid and must be repeated at 12–15 months (at least 3 months after the invalid dose).
In certain cases (e.g., outbreaks), the second dose can be given before age 4.
The minimum recommended interval between doses is 3 months, but if the second dose is given at least 28 days after the first, no repeat is needed.
Children under 13 who have received fewer than 2 doses should complete their schedule.
If the interval between doses exceeds the recommendation, the schedule does not need to restart.
Adolescents and adults:
Unvaccinated individuals aged 13+ without a history of chickenpox should receive two doses 4–8 weeks apart.
Those with one previous dose should get a second dose, at least 28 days apart.

CDC post-exposure recommendations for varicella:
CDC recommends vaccination for healthy, unvaccinated persons aged 12+ months without evidence of immunity within 5 days of exposure to reduce disease severity. Ideally within 3 days for over 90% protection.
A second dose post-exposure is recommended for those with only one prior dose, for better future protection.
Note: In Iran, chickenpox vaccination is not mandatory as it is not part of the national immunization program, and may increase the risk of shingles later in life.</item>

        <item>The best time for vaccination is late September to mid-October, but high-risk individuals (children under 2, people with AIDS, those 6 months–18 years on long-term aspirin) should be vaccinated whenever they visit. The Iranian FluGuard vaccine is not recommended for those under 18.</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>